Managers claim that inclusive
practices are already showing
benefits in ways far beyond
reputational enhancement.
These include productivity gains,
quality improvement, boost in innovative
capabilities, and growth
in employee engagement.
They've begun thinking more deeply about
leveraging the talents of all employees
through greater sensitivity
to individual needs.
Better pattern recognition
Large companies,
particularly tech companies,
have realized that they already had
neurodiverse talent on their staff.
Many of these employees contribute their
special skills in pattern recognition,
memory,
or mathematics on teams working
to solve highly complex problems.
In the fields of machine learning,
artificial intelligence, and data science,
neurodiverse employees have proven to
outperform their neurotypical counterparts.
Creative thinking
Variations in their neurological
constitution allows
neurodivergent employees to think
differently or out of the box.
They're able to see past the
conventional frameworks which
could limit the creativity
of neurotypical individuals.
Positive work environment or
an organization's reputation
According to the
training industry,
employers who have opened
their doors to a neurodiverse
workforce have found that
neurodiverse and autistic
employees have a retention
rate upwards of 90%.
Moreover, having neurodiverse
talent in your workforce
improves a company's external
as well as internal image.
When a brand has a strong purpose,
consumers are four times more likely to
trust the company and
six times more likely
to defend the
company from criticism.